<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://phileinsophos.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://phileinsophos.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-13T16:02:17+00:00</updated><id>https://phileinsophos.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Data Immutability in Data Protection</title><link href="https://phileinsophos.github.io/blog/2023/12/29/Data-immutability-in-data-protection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Immutability in Data Protection"/><published>2023-12-29T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-29T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phileinsophos.github.io/blog/2023/12/29/Data-immutability-in-data-protection</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phileinsophos.github.io/blog/2023/12/29/Data-immutability-in-data-protection/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="data-immutability-in-data-protection">Data Immutability in Data Protection</h1> <p>Data immutability is a critical aspect of data protection. It involves securing stored data on a protection device in a way that prevents unauthorized alterations or updates. The retention lock concept plays a pivotal role in achieving this security. Retention lock allows data to be locked for a specific duration, during which no user or intruder can modify the locked data until the lock expires.</p> <h2 id="forms-of-retention-lock">Forms of Retention Lock</h2> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Compliance Lock:</strong> Once enabled, this lock on data cannot be reversed. It is the strictest form, preventing the unlocking of data until the lock’s expiration.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Governance Lock:</strong> A less strict form wherein data remains locked until the specified time duration ends or until an administrator disables the lock.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Auto Retention Lock:</strong> Also known as the default retention lock, data is locked immediately upon backup and remains locked until a set cool-off period expires.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Indefinite Retention Lock:</strong> This lock keeps data locked indefinitely, useful for compliance or during legal disputes until resolution. Once enabled, the data remains locked without an expiry or until the cooling-off period ends.</p> </li> </ol> <h2 id="attack-vectors-on-backed-up-data">Attack Vectors on Backed-up Data</h2> <p>Several attack vectors or techniques can be employed to exploit backed-up or locked data:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Namespace Level Protection:</strong> Protects data within the file system namespace, preventing operations like renaming, modification, or deletion.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Clock Manipulation and NTP Servers:</strong> Attacker manipulation of server clocks or NTP access can alter retained data by adjusting time and date settings.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Backdoor Access via OS Shell:</strong> Access to the backup system’s OS shell can allow an attacker to execute destructive commands on the data.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Hypervisor Level Access:</strong> Inadequately secured hypervisor consoles grant access to data stores and virtual machine networks, enabling destructive commands.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Bootloader Level Access:</strong> Unsecured OS bootloaders provide direct access to the shell, making data vulnerable to exploitation.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>BIOS and Platform Management Interface:</strong> Unsecured interfaces provide remote access to the system, potentially compromising data stored on disks.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Data Center Access:</strong> Physical access to data centers allows attackers to destroy or manipulate data on disks.</p> </li> </ol> <h2 id="hardening-practices-for-enhanced-security">Hardening Practices for Enhanced Security</h2> <p>To strengthen system security, consider implementing the following practices:</p> <ul> <li>Restrict physical access to unauthorized personnel.</li> <li>Disconnect BIOS and platform management interfaces from the network. Randomize root credentials and implement temporary user logins for specific durations.</li> <li>Secure bootloaders by randomizing root passwords and restricting the ability to edit bootloader entries.</li> <li>Secure the OS shell by limiting user access to non-destructive commands or implementing time-based token access.</li> <li>Secure the hypervisor by blocking external access and tools like CLI, GUI, and ipmitool.</li> <li>Implement measures to secure clock and NTP settings by restricting frequency and number of modifications, requiring 2FA during NTP configurations, and enabling secure NTP to detect clock skew.</li> </ul> <p>These practices can significantly enhance the security of your system against potential attacks on backed-up data.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Retention-Lock"/><category term="data-protection"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[securing access to backed-up data]]></summary></entry></feed>